

Prague, Czech Republicpetr.penicka@gmail.com+66 098 1152 498

in linkedin.com/in/petr-penicka
 github.com/ppenicka
 ppenicka.me

ABOUT ME

Senior Frontend Engineer specializing in JavaScript technologies, most notably Vue.js, Nuxt.js, TypeScript and React. Before switching to software engineering, I gained 12+ years of experience in the tech industry as a Program Manager and a Technical Writer. This makes me stand out among other engineers due to exceptional communication, planning and organizational skills. If you're looking for an engineer who not only writes great code, but is also a pleasure to work with for colleagues in non-technical roles, I'm likely the right fit.

EXPERIENCE

2024 - present **Senior Frontend Engineer** Slash.Digital As a Senior Frontend Engineer at Slash. Digital, I'm developing high-exposure marketing websites and web applications that support clients' marketing campaigns and have significant impact on the growth of their business. Vue.js 3 / Nuxt.js / TypeScript / Tailwind / SCSS / SWRV / Wagtail CMS 2021 - 2024 Frontend Engineer Worked on projects including UI for the company's billing and invoicing system, UI for configuration of payment gateways and payment methods, CAPTCHAs, phone verification, 2-factor authentication, UI for configuring partner payout settings, modularization and migration of web apps to monorepo architecture. I had also led the migration of courier registration website from WordPress to a custom solution based on Nuxt.js and Prismic. Vue.js 2 / Vue.js 3 / Vuex / Vue Testing Library / Pinia / Nuxt.js /
Prismic / TypeScript / Sass / Tailwind / Element UI / Prismic CMS 2022 - 2023 Instructor Codeworks As a part-time gig during my main job at Glovo, I was tutoring at weekend classes of Codeworks, Barcelona's top rated software engineering bootcamp. JavaScript / TypeScript / React / Express / Node.js 2020 - 2021 Frontend Developer ManoMano Implemented redesign of the main product page (with traffic over 1M views per day), redesign of the main navigation menu, customisation of the UI for professional users, and migration of the codebase to TypeScript. React / Redux / Redux Saga / Next.js / Sass / Enzyme / React Testing Library / TypeScript 2016 - 2019 **Engineering Program Manager Red Hat** Managed the planning, development and delivery of 20+ releases of various Red Hat products. 2015 **Documentation Program Manager** Red Hat Managed a team of technical writers responsible for documentation of various Red Hat products. 2012 - 2014 **Technical Writer Red Hat** Authored and maintained documentation of Red Hat products. 2008 - 2012 **Technical Writer Kentico Software** Authored and maintained product documentation of Kentico CMS.

EDUCATION

EDUCATION		
2020	Software Engineering Immersive software engineering bootcamp focused on full-stace	Codeworks, Barcelona, Catalonia, ES k web development.
2013	Master's Degree in Applied Informatics Study field Service Science, Management and Engineering.	Masaryk University, Brno, CZ
2011	Bachelor's Degree in Applied Informatics Study field Applied Informatics.	Masaryk University, Brno, CZ

LANGUAGES

English - proficient (C2) Spanish - intermediate (B1) German - intermediate (B1)

Czech - native

CURRENT CAREER GOAL

Expand my client base so that I can utilize my full time capacity on interesting and technically challenging projects, in order to further establish myself as a recognized freelancer while maintaining stable growth of technical skills and expertise.